JITENDRA GARG

ENGINEERING MANAGER | SCRUM MASTER | AGILE COACH

PUNE, INDIA 412207 - +91 - 8277433277

jitendragarg@gmail.com - contact@jitendragarg.com - www.jitendragarg.com

PROFESSIONAL SUMMARY

I have 10+ years of IT industry experience and **6+ years of experience in leadership**. I have played multiple roles related to technical delivery in multiple domains while working on over 20+ technologies. I am currently focused on continuous improvement and agile project management. I am looking for a role allowing me to use the full gamut of my technical skills and my coaching and mentoring experience.

CORE COMPETENCIES

Technical Delivery - Able to deliver IT software and hardware products, keeping up with market trends

- Delivered 3 projects simultaneously while exceeding quality expectations of the customer
- Completed projects in multiple technologies including machine learning and blockchain
- Acheived 90% success rate over 6+ years delivering 30+ projects ahead of schedule

Team Growth - Promoting continuous improvement and continuous learning

- Implemented upskilling plans and promoted regular coaching and mentoring
- Acted as mentor and training manager for colleagues at both junior and senior level
- Championed and supported agile values advancing organizational agility

Stakeholder Engagement - Able to manage multiple stakeholders from multiple backgrounds

- Engaged with C-level executives working closely to reach organizational goals.
- Experienced in working in conjunction with customer to improve the feedback cycle
- Pursued continuous involvement of stakeholders during project execution phase

Delivery Process Optimization - Capable of using industry standard practices to improve delivery

- Coached senior management including C-level executives on code quality standards
- Improved business process of end customer using Lean principles to reduce waste
- Prepared and enacted contingency plan, business continuation plan, and IT service roadmap.

MANAGEMENT SKILLS

Planning - Delivery Planning, Effort and Cost Estimation, Risk Mitigation Planning, Resource Planning

Delivery - Technical Delivery Management, Stakeholder Management, Earned Value Management

Team - Upskilling, Hiring Management, Technical Training, Conflict Management, Coaching

Framework - SCRUM, Waterfall, Kanban, Lean, XP

CERTIFICATIONS

Professional Scrum Master 1 by Scrum.org

Infosys Scrum Master by Infosys India

Academic English Proficiency Level 8.0 by IELTS

TECHNICAL SKILLS

Primary Language - C#, ASP.Net, WCF, Web Api 2, HTML5, Javascript, Jquery

Cloud Services - Azure IaaS, Azure PaaS, Azure Machine Learning, Azure IoT, Google Domains

Tools - Visual Studio, VS Code, SQL Server, Jira, Postman, TFS, Sonargube, Jenkins, Git, Trello, Slack

Others - ASP.Net MVC, WPF, VB.Net, Winforms, Windows Service, CSS3, Solidity, .Net Core, Unity 3D, Xamarin, MS Dynamics 365, Joomla, Wordpress, Flutter.js, Angular 2

EDUCATION

MAULANA AZAD NATIONAL INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY, BHOPAL - JUNE 2003 - MAY 2007

Bachelor of Technology in Information Technology - 7.58 GPA

WORK EXPERIENCE

Sonata Software Limited, Bangalore - Senior Project Manager

April 2021 - To Date

Digital Convergence Technologies, Pune - Project Manager

October 2019 - January 2020

- Executed strategies to improve technical delivery process and cut down risks by 30%
- Implemented upskilling plan to improve technical capabilities of delivery team
- Successfully delivered new features to customer in 60% of estimated effort
- Updated KRAs and KPIs to promote continuous learning and improvement

Nexshore Technologies, Bangalore - Team Leader

June 2018 - May 2019

- Won a project from Karnataka's tourism department, delivering newsworthy hardware solutions
- Delivered cloud storage solution akin Google Drive designed from scratch within 3 months
- Acted as hiring and training manager for internship program for technical colleges
- Implemented proof of concept application in Ethereum Blockchain using Azure workbench

Vidushi Software Solutions, Valsad - Technical Lead .Net

August 2017 - May 2018

- Executed Scrum at Scale and conducted Agile coaching for senior management to improve agility
- Delivered 3 products from scratch with a quality rating of A+, higher than expected B rating
- Led organization wide upskilling program to reach 30% certified employees from 2%
- Implemented proof of concept application in Machine Learning and Sharepoint

Melstar Infotech, Pune - Technical Analyst

July 2016 - January 2017

- Led a team of 20+ employees including DevOps, Business Analysts, IT and support staff
- Put contingency plans into practice to improve system availability to 99.5% from 90%
- Owned and led a major product working on transactions over 200 million USD
- Updated coaching and mentoring program, upskilling 60% employees over 3 months

AISOFT Technologies, Bangalore - Project Leader

August 2014 - December 2015

- Enacted and executed mentoring program for trainee and junior technical staff
- Provided consultation for IT service roadmap, development and release planning
- Managed outsourcing operations of Veritas Petroleum Services as account manager
- Built a team from new hires and led them to a successful delivery for a major product

HUDE Labs, Bhopal - Lead Technical Consultant

October 2012 - August 2014

- Created go-to-market strategy for multiple products including e-commerce store
- Consulted with end customers for technical delivery and release schedule planning
- Implemented industry standard code quality checks and peer review processes
- Championed UX driven design and test driven development across organization

Wipro Technologies, Bangalore - Project Engineer

July 2007 - February 2012

- Won a project from a competing vendor worth 2 million USD acting as project lead
- Automated fixes for key problem areas, freeing 40% of development effort
- Won "Key Talent" award in 2007 for performing above expectations during training
- Coached and mentored colleagues on code quality and good programming practices

EXTRA CURRICULAR

Created official website of alma mater (www.manit.ac.in)

Acted as Technical Supervisor for MANIT Student Council

Co-created a social platform for hindi speakers (www.myhindiforum.com)